Contact

Wazirabad, Punjab, Pakistan 03084244302 (Work) ranaabobakarit@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ranaabobakar (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

JavaScript Node.js Linux

Certifications

Rest API Using MongoDB and NodeJS: Beginners Guide

The JavaScript Complete Guide Course

Introduction to Linux
Network Fundamentals
Bash Scripting Basics

RANA ABOBAKAR

Back End Developer (JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js MongoDB, MySQL, Linux)

Wazirabad

Summary

I am a Back End Developer, I have 3 years of experience in Information Technology and 1-year of experience in JavaScript, Node.js/Express.js. I am a very hardworking and self-motivated individual who enjoys a challenge, achieving personal goals and objectives. I work well with others as part of a team and individual. Still eager to adapt and learn new languages. My goal is to become an IT Administrator.

Expert in the following skill-set:

Programming & Scripting Languages: JavaScript, C/C++, C#.

Web Development Frameworks/Libraries:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Mongoose, Sequelize(ORM), Jest.

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB.

Development Tools & IDEs: VSCode.

Other Tools: git, GitHub, Trello.

Experience

Codek Technologies

9 months

Back End Developer

November 2021 - March 2022 (5 months)

Gujrat District, Punjab, Pakistan

Back End Developer

July 2021 - November 2021 (5 months)

Gujrāt, Punjab, Pakistan

During my Internship, I learned JavaScript, Node.js/Express.js

MongoDB(Mongoose), and much more.

I learned Express.js Routing and creating APIs and learned how APIs work, performed CRUD operations on MongoDB DataBase.

I learned JWT for Authentication and Authorization.

I learned Unit Testing with the help of the JEST Library.

Page 1 of 2

I learned Google API for Uploading images on Google Drive.

Education

University of Gujrat

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology · (September 2019 - August 2023)